<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>

<!--  Use this to test local rendering in firefox -->
<!-- <?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?> -->

<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="Jetty">

	<release projectid="rt.jetty" version="7.0.0.x"/>
	
   	<introduction>
	    <html:p>
			Jetty is an open-source, standards-based, full-featured web server implemented entirely in Java.
		</html:p>
						
		<html:p>
			The plan deals with the important matters of release deliverables, release milestones,			
			target operating environments, and release-to-release compatibility. 
			These are all things that need to be clear for any release, even if no features were to change.
	    </html:p>
  	</introduction>
 	
	<release_deliverables>
    	<html:p>
    		TBD with regard to eclipse deliverables.  We will continue to publish artifacts into the central maven repository
    		as we have done all along for our other user bases.  Primary download bundles will be determined as well but we intend to retain
    		our traditional jetty download bundle in addition to other eclipse oriented packaging.
    	</html:p>
  	</release_deliverables>

  	
	<release_milestones> 		
		<preamble>
			<html:p>      
  				Release milestones will be occurring at roughly 4-6 week intervals.
  			</html:p>
		</preamble>
		   		   				
		<milestone date="03/04/2009" milestone="M0"><html:div>7.0.0.M0</html:div>- published</milestone>
		<milestone date="06/05/2009" milestone="M1"><html:div>7.0.0.M1</html:div></milestone>
		
 		<postamble>
			<html:div>
				<html:p>
					Individual, milestone level plans for the components that make up the Eclipse Project can be found 
		  			on the <html:a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/Jetty/ProjectPlan">Jetty Project Plan page</html:a>
		  			on the Eclipse wiki.
		  		</html:p>
				<html:p>
					Our target is to release a 7.0.0.x release based on the servlet api version 2.5 as soon as we graduate incubation.
					We also intend to release a version 8.0.0.x of jetty based on the servlet api version 3.0 once that is available
					and maintain parallel development on these two codebases, exactly how jetty development has proceeded historically.
	  			</html:p>
			</html:div>
		</postamble>

	</release_milestones>
 		
	<target_environments>
		<html:p>
			Jetty closely follows the requirements of the servlet-api version that it implements and works with.  As such JDK/JRE versions and other dependency versions are dictated to us by the spec in question.
		</html:p>	
				
		<html:p>
			So, the Jetty project will support:
			<html:ul>
	    		<html:li>Eclipse Platform 3.4.x and up</html:li>
	    		<html:li>JDK/JRE 1.5.x and 1.6.x</html:li>
	    	</html:ul>	
  		</html:p>
  		
 		<internationalization>
    		<html:p>     			
     			Jetty does not currently ship with internationalized exceptions or documentation. 
     		</html:p>
 		</internationalization>
  		    		
	</target_environments>
 		 		
 	<compatibility_with_previous_releases>
 		<html:p>Packaging changes (org.mortbay.jetty -> org.eclipse.jetty) have broken the seamless transition from previous versions of jetty.</html:p>
 	</compatibility_with_previous_releases>
 	
 	<themes_and_priorities>
 	
   		<preamble>
   			<html:p>
   				The project has identified major areas of work, that will be the
   				priorities for this development cycle. 
   			</html:p>
   		</preamble>	 
   			  
		<theme name="Process Migration">
		
			<description>
				<html:p>
					Jetty has existed outside of eclipse for longer then eclipse has existed.  As such processes have 
					been in place for working with and on Jetty for many years and we must strive to align our project
					more with 'the eclipse way' while still supporting our wide variety of existing users.  (this is 
					largely an example theme)
										
					<html:ul>
						<html:li>
							review jetty ip database for validity
							<html:a href="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/show_bug.cgi?id=270509">270509</html:a>
						</html:li>								
					</html:ul>  					
						
				</html:p>
			</description>			
		</theme>    			  
   			    
	</themes_and_priorities>
			
</plan>
